Every second chance begins with a first step.
Step Up is a music, drama, romance film directed by Anne Fletcher.
Delinquent Tyler Gage receives the opportunity of a lifetime after vandalizing a performing arts school,
gaining him the chance to earn a scholarship and dance with up-and-coming dancer Nora.
Tyler Gage, played by Channing Tatum.
Nora Clark, played by Jenna Dewan.
Mac Carter, played by Damaine Radcliff.
Director Gordon, played by Rachel Griffiths.
Katherine Clark, played by Deirdre Lovejoy.
Camille Gage, played by Alyson Stoner.
Step Up is a 2006 American teen dance drama film directed by Anne
Fletcher and written by Duane Adler and Melissa Rosenberg.
The film stars Channing Tatum, Jenna Dewan, Mario
Barrett, Drew Sidora, and Rachel Griffiths.
Set in Baltimore, Maryland, the film follows the tale of the disadvantaged Tyler Gage and the privileged modern
dancer Nora Clark, who find themselves paired up in a showcase that determines both of their futures.
Realizing that they only have one chance, they finally work together.
Step Up was released in the United States on August 11,
2006, by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, and became a box office
success, grossing $114 million against a budget of $12 million.
It spawned a franchise that includes four sequels and a television series.
The film explores themes of dancing, dance, new
love, baltimore, usa, art school.
The tone is emotional.